Mark Tinker NYPD Blue Collection
Mark Tinker NYPD Blue Collection
1994-2002
Tinker, Mark
14 linear ft.
Scripts and production notes for the television drama NYPD Blue
2534130
Biographical History
NYPD Blue is a police drama from producer Steven Bochco (Hill Street Blues, LA Law) that mixes action with cops' personal lives. Premiering in September 1993, NYPD Blue weathered early criticism from Christian watchdog groups and ABC station affiliates for its adult language and partial nudity to become one of network television's most critically acclaimed programs. The show is widely recognized for its realism, brilliant writing, exceptional acting, and treatment of controversial subject matter. It has received more than 80 Emmy nominations, winning 19.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Mark Tinker NYPD Blue Collection contains Scripts and production notes for most of the seasons (scripts and production notes from Seasons 1, 4, and 10 are not included within the collection). The four-digit production number for each episode is given in parenthesis ( ).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged in order by season and, within each season, by air date. Production notes can be found at the end of each season.
Related Material
has a number of television-related collections. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
Videotapes of 193 episodes from seasons 2 thorugh 9 have been removed from the collection and shelved in Media Services. Please contact the repository listed above for further information.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Tinker, Mark.; NYPD Blue (television series); Popular culture -- United States.; Television -- Production and direction.; Television -- United States.; Television series -- United States.; Scripts (documents); Notes (documents); Television producers and directors.
Access Restrictions
The collection is currently CLOSED. It will reopen in May of 2020.
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mark Tinker, director of the series.
Inventory
- Scripts and production books
  - Season 2
    - Episode 2-1 (0V01) TRIALS & TRIBULATIONS, 10/11/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-2 (0V02) FOR WHOM THE SKELL TOLLS, 10/18/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-3 (0V03) COP SUEY, 10/25/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-4 (0V04) DEAD & GONE, 11/1/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-5 (0V05) FINAL ADJUSTMENT, 11/22/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-6 (0V06) DOUBLE ABANDANDO, 11/29/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-7 (0V07) SIMONE SAYS, 11/15/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-8 (0V08) YOU BET YOUR LIFE, 12/6/1994 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-9 (0V09) DON WE NOW OUR GAY APPAREL, 1/3/1995 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-10 (0V10) IN THE BUTT, BOB, 1/10/1995 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-11 (0V11) VISHY VASHY VINNIE, 1/17/1995 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-12 (0V12) LARGE MOUTH BASS, 2/7/1995 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-13 (0V13) TRAVELS WITH ANDY, 2/14/1995 (Box 1)
    - Episode 2-14 (0V14) A MURDER WITH TEETH IN IT, 2/21/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-15 (0V15) BOMB'S AWAY, 2/28/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-16 (0V16) UNAMERICAN GRAFFITI, 3/14/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-17 (0V17) DIRTY SOCKS, 3/21/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-18 (0V18) INNUENDO, 4/4/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-19 (0V19) BOXER REBELLION, 5/2/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-20 (0V20) THE BOOKIE & KOOKY COOKIE, 5/9/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-21 (0V21) THE BANK DICK, 5/16/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 2-22 (0V22) A.D.A. SIPOWITZ, 5/23/1995 (Box 2)
    - 2nd SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes production schedules, weekly status reports, Nielsen Ranking Reports, spotting notes, and air dates (Box 2)
  - Season 3
    - Episode 3-1 (0G01) E.R., 10/24/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 3-2 (0G02) TORAH! TORAH! TORAH!, 10/31/1995 (Box 2)
    - Episode 3-3 (0G03) ONE BIG HAPPY FAMILY, 11/7/1995 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-4 (0G04) HEAVEN CAN WAIT, 11/14/1995 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-5 (0G05) DIRTY LAUNDRY, 11/21/1995 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-6 (0G06) CURT RUSSELL, 11/28/1995 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-7 (0G07) AGING BULL, 12/12/1995 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-8 (0G08) COLD HEATERS, 12/19/1995 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-9 (0G09) SORRY, WONG SUSPECT, 1/9/1996 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-10 (0G10) THE BACKBOARD JUNGLE, 1/16/1996 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-11 (0G11) BURNIN' LOVE, 1/30/1996 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-12 (0G12) THESE OLD BONES, 2/6/1996 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-13 (0G13) A TUSHFUL OF DOLLARS, 2/13/1996 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-14 (0G14) THE NUTTY CONFESSOR, 2/20/1996 (Box 3)
    - Episode 3-15 (0G15) HEAD CASE, 2/27/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-16 (0G16) GIRL TALK, 3/19/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-17 (0G17) HOLLIE & THE BLOWFISH, 3/26/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-18 (0G18) WE WAS ROBBED, 4/2/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-19 (0G19) AUNTIE MAIMED, 4/30/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-20 (0G20) A DEATH IN THE FAMILY, 5/7/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-21 (0G21) CLOSING TIME, 5/14/1996 (Box 4)
    - Episode 3-22 (0G22) HE'S NOT GUILTY, HE'S MY BROTHER, 5/21/1996 (Box 4)
    - 3rd SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes shooting schedules, status reports, correspondence, cost summaries, and scripts (Box 4)
  - Season 5
    - Episode 5-1 (0T01) THIS BUD'S FOR YOU, 9/30/1997 (Box 4)
    - Episode 5-2 (0T02) ALL'S WELLS THAT ENDS WELLS, 10/7/1997 (Box 4)
    - Episode 5-3 (0T03) THREE GIRLS AND A BABY, 10/14/1997 (Box 4)
    - Episode 5-4 (0T04) THE TRUTH IS OUT THERE, 10/28/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-5 (0T05) IT TAKES A VILLAGE, 11/4/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-6 (0T06) DEAD MAN TALKING, 11/11/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-7 (0T07) SHEEDY DEALINGS, 11/18/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-8 (0T08) LOST ISRAEL [PART I], 11/25/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-9 (0T09) LOST ISRAEL [PART II], 12/9/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-10 (0T10) REMEMBRANCE OF HUMPS PAST, 12/16/1997 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-11 (0T11) YOU'RE UNDER A RASTA, 1/6/1998 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-12 (0T12) A BOX OF WENDY, 1/13/1998 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-13 (0T13) TWIN PETES, 2/10/1998 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-14 (0T14) WEAVER OF HATE, 2/17/1998 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-15 (0T15) DON'T KILL THE MESSENGER, 2/24/1998 (Box 5)
    - Episode 5-16 (0T16) THE ONE THAT GOT AWAY, 3/3/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 5-17 (0T17) SPEAK FOR YOURSELF, BRUCE CLAYTON, 3/24/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 5-18 (0T18) I DON'T WANNA DYE, 3/31/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 5-19 (0T19) PROSTRATE BEFORE THE LAW, 4/28/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 5-20 (0T20) HAMMER TIME, 5/5/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 5-21 (0T21) SEMINAL THINKING, 5/12/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 5-22 (0T22) HONEYMOON AT VIAGRA FALLS, 5/19/1998 (Box 6)
    - 5th SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes shooting schedules, production reports, contact lists, correspondence, cost summaries, and scripts (Box 6)
  - Season 6
    - Episode 6-1 (0C01) TOP GUM, 10/20/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 6-2 (0c01) COP IN A BOTTLE, 10/27/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 6-3 (0c03) NUMB & NUMBER, 11/10/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 6-4 (0C04) BROTHER'S KEEPER, 11/17/1998 (Box 6)
    - Episode 6-5 (0C05) HEART AND SOULS, 11/24/1998 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-6 (0C06) DANNY BOY, 12/1/1998 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-7 (0C07) CZECH BOUNCER, 12/8/1998 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-8 (0C08) RAGING BULLS, 12/15/1998 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-9 (0C09) GRIME SCENE, 1/5/1998 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-10 (0C10) SHOW AND TELL, 1/12/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-11 (0C11) THE BIG BANG THEORY, 2/9/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-12 (0C12) WHAT'S UP CHUCK?, 2/16/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-13 (0C13) DEAD GIRL WALKING, 2/23/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-14 (0C14) RAFAEL'S INFERNO, 3/2/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-15 (0C15) I HAVE A DREAM, 4/6/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-16 (0C16) TAIN'T MISBEHAVIN', 4/13/1999 (Box 7)
    - Episode 6-17 (0C17) DON'T METH WITH ME, 4/20/1999 (Box 8)
    - Episode 6-18 (0C18) MR. ROBERTS, 4/27/1999 (Box 8)
    - Episode 6-19 (0C19) JUDAS PRIEST, 5/4/1999 (Box 8)
    - Episode 6-20 (0C20) I'LL DRAW YOU A MAPP, 5/11/1999 (Box 8)
    - Episode 6-21 (0C21) VOIR DIRE THIS, 5/18/1999 (Box 8)
    - Episode 6-22 (0C22) SAFE HOME, 5/25/1999 (Box 8)
    - 6th SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes daily production status reports, scripts, and shooting schedules (Box 8)
  - Season 7
    - Episode 7-1 (0E01) LOOGIE NIGHTS, 1/11/2000 (Box 8)
    - Episode 7-2 (0E02) A HOLE IN JUAN, 1/18/2000 (Box 8)
    - Episode 7-3 (0E03) THE MAN WITH TWO RIGHT SHOES, 1/25/2000 (Box 8)
    - Episode 7-4 (0E04) THE NAKED AND THE DEAD, 2/1/2000 (Box 8)
    - Episode 7-5 (0E05) THESE SHOOTS ARE MADE FOR JOAQUIN, 2/8/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-6 (0E06) BROTHERS UNDER ARMS, 2/15/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-7 (0E07) ALONG CAME JONES, 2/22/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-8 (0E08) EVERYBODY PLAYS THE MULE, 2/23/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-9 (0E09) JACKASS, 2/29/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-10 (0E10) WHO MURDERS SLEEP, 3/7/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-11 (0E11) LITTLE ABNER, 3/14/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-12 (0E12) WELCOME TO NEW YORK, 3/21/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-13 (0E13) THE IRVIN FILES, 3/28/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-14 (0E14) SLEEP OVER, 4/4/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-15 (0E15) STRESSED FOR SUCCESS, 4/11/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-16 (0E16) GOOD-BYE CHARLIE, 4/18/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-17 (0E17) ROLL OUT THE BARREL, 4/25/2000 (Box 9)
    - Episode 7-18 (0E18) LUCKY LUCIANO, 5/2/2000 (Box 10)
    - Episode 7-19 (0E19) TEA AND SYMPATHY, 5/9/2000 (Box 10)
    - Episode 7-20 (0E20) THIS OLD SPOUSE, 5/16/2000 (Box 10)
    - Episode 7-21 (0E21) BATS OFF TO LARRY, 5/23/2000 (Box 10)
    - Episode 7-22 (0E22) THE LAST ROUND UP, 5/23/2000 (Box 10)
    - 7th SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes daily production status reports, shooting schedules, call sheets, contact lists, scripts, air dates, and cost summaries (Box 10)
  - Season 8
    - Episode 8-1 (EA01) DAVELESS IN NEW YORK, 1/9/2001 (Box 10)
    - Episode 8-2 (EA02) WAKING UP IS HARD TO DO, 1/16/2001 (Box 10)
    - Episode 8-3 (EA03) FRANCO MY DEAR, I DON'T GIVE A DAMN, 1/23/2001 (Box 10)
    - Episode 8-4 (EA04) FAMILY TIES, 1/30/2001 (Box 10)
    - Episode 8-5 (EA05) FOOLS RUSSIAN, 2/6/2001 (Box 10)
    - Episode 8-6 (EA06) WRITING WRONGS, 2/13/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-7 (EA07) IN-LAWS, OUTLAWS, 2/20/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-8 (EA08) RUSSELLMANIA, 2/27/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-9 (EA09) OH GOLLY GOTH, 3/6/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-10 (EA10) IN THE STILL OF THE NIGHT, 3/13/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-11 (EA11) PEEPING TOMMY, 3/20/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-12 (EA12) THUMB ENCHANTED EVENING, 3/27/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-13 (EA13) FLIGHT OF FANCY, 4/3/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-14 (EA14) NARIZ A NARIZ, 4/10/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-15 (EA15) LOVE HURTS, 4/17/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-16 (EA16) EVERYONE INTO THE POOLE, 4/24/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-17 (EA17) DYING TO TESTIFY, 5/1/2001 (Box 11)
    - Episode 8-18 (EA18) LOST TIME, 5/8/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 8-19 (EA19) UNDER COVERS, 5/15/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 8-20 (EA20) IN THE WIND, 5/22/2001 (Box 12)
    - 8th SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes cost summaries, correspondence, call sheets, daily production reports, shooting schedules, contact lists, and scripts (Box 12)
  - Season 9
    - Episode 9-1 (GA01) LIE LIKE A RUG, 11/6/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 9-2 (GA02) JOHNNY GOT HIS GOLD, 11/6/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 9-3 (GA03) TWO CLARKS IN A BAR, 11/13/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 9-4 (GA04) HIT THE ROAD, CLARK, 11/20/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 9-5 (GA05) COPS AND ROBBER, 11/27/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 9-6 (GA06) BABY LOVE, 12/4/2001 (Box 12)
    - Episode 9-7 (GA07) MOMS AWAY, 12/11/2001 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-8 (GA08) PUPPY LOVE, 12/18/2001 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-9 (GA09) HERE COMES THE SON, 1/8/2002 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-10 (GA10) JEALOUS HEARTS, 1/15/2002 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-11 (GA11) HUMPTY DUMPED, 2/5/2002 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-12 (GA12) OH, MAMA, 2/19/2002 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-13 (GA13) SAFARI, SO GOOD, 2/26/2002 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-14 (GA14) HAND JOB, 3/5/2002 (Box 13)
    - Episode 9-15 (GA15) GUNS AND HOSES, 3/12/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-16 (GA16) A LITTLE DAD'LL DO YA, 3/19/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-17 (GA17) GYPSY WOE'S ME, 3/26/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-18 (GA18) LESS IS MORTE, 4/16/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-19 (GA19) LOW BLOW, 4/30/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-20 (GA20) OEDIPUS WRECKED, 5/7/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-21 (GA21) DEAD MEAT IN NEW DELI, 5/14/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-22 (GA22) BETTER LAID THAN NEVER [PART I], 5/21/2002 (Box 14)
    - Episode 9-23 (GA23) BETTER LAID THAN NEVER [PART II], 5/21/2002 (Box 14)
    - 9th SEASON PRODUCTION BOOK, Includes correspondence, cost summaries, call sheets, daily production status reports, shooting schedules, and scripts (Box 14)